sri.com 2019-12-10

# Privacy Policy | SRI International

SRI International ("SRI", "we", "us") is a nonprofit organization that performs research and development activities for a broad range of customers. The Internet sites linking to this Privacy Policy (the "Sites") are operated and maintained by SRI. SRI is the "controller" and responsible for personal information processed in connection with the use of the Sites.

This Privacy Policy sets out what information that we may collect from you, why and when we process and share that information, and your related rights. **By visiting our Sites, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.**

Our Sites are not designed nor intended to attract children under the age of 18. If you are not at least 18-years-old, do not use our Sites. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If we learn that personal information of persons less than 13 years-of-age has been inadvertently collected through our Sites, we will take the appropriate steps to delete this information.

## What information SRI collects about you

We may collect several types of information from and about the users of our Sites, including:

**Categories of Personal Data** | **Examples**  
---|---  
**Personal Information** | Personally identifiable information **** that enables us to identify you, directly or indirectly, by reference to an identifier, including but not limited to your name, company name, postal address, e-mail address, telephone number, identification number, online identifier, or one or more factors specific to you  
**Usage Information** | Information related to your access to, visit or use of, or interaction with SRI’s Sites, including but not limited to IP address; web page you last visited; computer and connection information such as browser type and version, operating system, and platform; software or database download activity; and frequency of your visits to our Sites  
**User Contributions** | Information provided by you to be published on our Sites including but not limited to any information you post on the SRI blog  
  
## How SRI collects information about you

**Personal Information** will be collected through information that you knowingly provide to us by filling in the forms on our Sites or when you otherwise interact with us. This Personal Information may include any information you provide at the time of registering on our Sites, subscribing to our newsletters, posting materials, downloading software or data, or requesting further information. Personal Information is transferred securely via HTTPS ( _secure_ HTTP) protocol and may be transferred internationally for processing and storage. Personal Information includes any Usage Information and User Contributions to the extent such information can be used to identify you either directly or when combined with the Personal Information you provide to us.

Some **Usage Information** may be collected through the use of cookies. Please reference the cookie section below for more information.

**User Contributions** are posted on our Sites and transmitted to others at your own risk. We cannot control the actions of other users of our Sites with whom you may choose to share your User Contributions.

## When and why SRI collects, uses, and shares information about you

SRI will only collect, use, and share Personal Information, Usage Information, and User Contributions under certain circumstances.

**Personal Data** | **Why SRI Processes Such Data** | **Legal Basis for Processing**  
---|---|---  
**Contact information or personal identifiers**  
(e.g., name, job title, company name, postal address, e-mail address, phone number, or other personal identifiers) | 

  * To respond to your questions, comments, or requests
  * To communicate with you about SRI or its products and/or services
  * To administer marketing efforts (e.g., newsletters, e-mails, industry updates)
  * To address technical or security issues
  * To comply with applicable laws or protect your vital interests

| 

  * Consent
  * Necessity to perform a contract (e.g., for SRI to provide you a service)
  * Necessity for legal compliance (e.g., when SRI receives a court order) or to protect your vital interests (e.g., medical emergencies)
  * Necessity to pursue SRI’s legitimate interests (provided your interests or fundamental rights do not override such interests)

**Employment information**  
(e.g., employment status or history, education history, and other personal data you submit in applying for a job at SRI) | 

  * To process your request in having SRI consider your job application
  * To evaluate your job application, including but not limited to performing background checks using a third-party service provider

| 

  * Consent
  * Necessity to perform a contract
  * Necessity to pursue SRI’s legitimate interests to extent allowable

**Device, browser, or usage information**  
(e.g., IP addresses; web page last visited; computer and connection information such as browser type and version, operating system, and platform; software or database download activity; and frequency of visits to our Sites) | 

  * To monitor quality control
  * To ensure compliance with any and all applicable laws and SRI contracts
  * To ensure network and information security
  * To improve your user experience with our Sites, products, and/or services

| 

  * Consent
  * Necessity to pursue SRI’s legitimate interests to extent allowable

**Information provided by you to be published on our Sites** | 

  * To process information that you want published on our Sites

| 

  * Consent
  * Necessity to pursue SRI’s legitimate interests to extent allowable

SRI has established and maintains reasonable procedures to protect the confidentiality, security, and integrity of Personal Information and Usage Information collected through our Sites. SRI will not sell or rent your Personal Information to anyone.

Data retention of e-mail addresses collected for marketing purposes is based on recency of the last open or click-through. Recipients who have not opened or clicked-through an e-mail from SRI within 18 months will be removed from our database.

## Sharing information about you

There are circumstances where we wish to disclose or are compelled to disclose your Personal Information. This will only take place in accordance with applicable law and for the purposes listed above.

SRI may disclose your Personal Information:

  * within SRI to provide you with requested services and/or products or to comply with applicable laws;
  * with our third-party vendors, suppliers, and service providers that support or help manage our business;
  * with our affiliates or business partners with whom we enter commercial contracts;
  * with legal entities in the event of a joint venture, collaboration, financing, sale, merger, reorganization, change of legal form, dissolution or similar event;
  * with governmental, judicial, and/or law enforcement authorities as required or as permitted by law to protect the rights, property, or safety of ourselves, our customers, or others, as necessary; and/or
  * with any other third party where you have provided your consent (if required by applicable law)

If you use any of our scientific databases (e.g., BioCyc, MetaCyc, EcoCyc, and HumanCyc) or related software (e.g., Pathway Tools), please note that from time to time the U.S. Government may request, and SRI may disclose, personal data pertaining to your use of SRI’s scientific databases and software, which may include any data you provide us such as your contact information, institution name, and website activity. SRI operates and maintains such databases with funding by the U.S. Government, particularly the National Institutes of Health. For more information about disclosures related to such databases, please refer to the applicable terms and conditions that a user must review and accept in order to download information.

## Cookie usage, including how SRI collects information for remarketing with Google

Cookies are small files containing a string of characters that we may store on your computer or mobile device when you visit our Sites to improve your online experience. When you visit our Sites again, the cookies allow SRI to recognize your browser. Cookies may store your preferences and other information but cannot read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites.

When you first access our Sites, you will receive a pop-up that informs you of SRI’s use of cookies and that requests your opt-in consent to such use. You do not have to accept cookies, and consent can be withdrawn at any time. However, unless you have adjusted your browser so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you direct your browser to our Sites.

Below are links to learn more about how to adjust your browser settings for the most popular browsers:

When visiting our Sites, the following are some of the cookies that may be placed unless you choose to opt out:

**Key** | **Description** | **Domain** | **Expiration**  
---|---|---|---  
_gid | Google Analytics sets these cookies to both identify and throttle requests. | www.sri.com | 26 months  
_ga |   |   | 24 hours  
_gat |   |   | 10 minutes  
has_js | 

Drupal uses this cookie to indicate whether or not the visitor’s browser has JavaScript enabled.

| 

www.sri.com

| 

23 days  
  
vuid | 

Vimeo is a video sharing website. The embedded Vimeo player uses cookies to check if certain features or preferences have been selected by the user.

| 

vimeo.com

| 

24 months  
  
_atuvc

| 

AddThis is a social sharing widget to enable visitors to share content with a range of networking and sharing platforms. This cookie stores an updated page share count.

| 

addthis.com

| 

24 months  
  
APISID

| 

YouTube sets cookies for embedded videos to register anonymous statistical data. This includes tracking how many times the video is displayed and what settings are used for playback.

| 

youtube.com

| 

24 months  
  
HSID

|  |  | 

24 months  
  
LOGIN_INFO

|  |  | 

24 months  
  
CONSENT

|  |  | 

20 years and 1 month  
  
PREF

|  |  | 

8 months  
  
SAPISID

|  |  | 

24 months  
  
SID

|  |  | 

24 months  
  
SSID

|  |  | 

24 months  
  
VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE

|  |  | 

8 months  
  
YSC

|  |  | 

Session  
  
**Specific to Google:**

  * SRI advertises with Google Remarketing, which displays ads across the Web to users who may have visited our Sites in the past or have shown interest in specific products or information within our Sites.
  * Third-party vendors, including Google, may use cookies to serve ads on sites across the Internet based on past activity and visits to www.sri.com.
  * Visitors may opt out of Google’s use of cookies by visiting the Ads Preferences Manager. Alternatively, you may opt out of a third-party vendor’s use of cookies by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page.

## International transfers of Personal Information

SRI is headquartered in the United States. Information you provide will be stored on our servers located in the United States. Your Personal Information may be accessed by us or transferred to us in the United States or to our affiliates, partners, or service providers who are located worldwide. If you are visiting our Sites or accessing our products and services from outside the United States, be aware that your information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States where our servers are located and our central database is operated.

Where we transfer EU Personal Information to a third party located in a country not recognized by the EU Commission as ensuring an adequate level of protection, we will take appropriate steps, such as implementing standard contractual clauses recognized by the EU Commission, to safeguard such Personal Information.

## Third-party links

Our Sites may, from time to time, contain links to and from third-party websites. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites may have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any Personal Information to these websites.

## How to Opt-Out of Data Collection, Sharing, and Marketing Communications

If you do not want SRI to collect or process your Personal Information, including Usage Information and User Contributions, please (a) refuse all browser cookies; (b) ensure you have opted-out of all other non-essential cookies; and (c) do not fill out any forms or download any software or data on our Sites.

Even if you have given prior consent for collection or processing of your Personal Information in the past, you can always withdraw consent for future collection and processing.

If you do not want SRI to share your Personal Information with third parties or to send you any further marketing or related communications, please (a) use any opt-out functionality provided on relevant communications or on our Sites, (b) send a request via  https://www.sri.com/contact/form, or (c) click here to opt out.

## Managing your data

To request access, erasure, or rectification or to object to processing of your Personal Information, please contact us using one of the options provided below. Along with your specific request, please provide the contact information you provided to SRI when you performed downloads on our Sites or signed up to receive SRI communications.

Any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy – including requests to learn more about the purposes or legal bases under which SRI processes personal data, how SRI protects personal data, or your rights under this Privacy Policy – may also be directed to any of the contact options below.

**Online Form** | https://www.sri.com/contact/form  
---|---  
**E-mail** | privacy [at] sri.com  
**Post** | SRI International  
Attn: Legal Department  
333 Ravenswood Avenue  
Menlo Park, CA 94025-3493  
United States  
  
If you believe that SRI has not complied with its obligation under European law, you have the right to make a complaint to your EU Data Protection Authority.

## Updates to the privacy policy

SRI may need to update this Privacy Policy from time to time. Please return to the Sites regularly to check for any changes.

Policy last updated on May 14, 2019.
